Sankar S

UI Developer/Front End Developer

Contact Info

Address

HSR Layout, Bangalore, India 560034

Phone

+91 9688472518

E-mail

sssankarsam@gmail.com

LinkedIn

<u>linkedin.com/in/sankar-ui-developer</u>

Website

https://sankarsans.github.io/

Skills

- HTML/HTML5
- CSS3/SASS/SCSS
- Angular 2+, Angular Material, PrimeNg
- JavaScript
- TypeScript, jQuery
- Bootstrap, CSS Flexbox, Media Query
- REST API, Postman, Swagger Testing
- JSON, Chart.js, RxJS
- GitHub, Bitbucket
- JWT, Token-Based Authentications
- Azure Devops, CI/CD Process
- SEO, Accessibility Testing
- MySql, Cosmos Db
- Figma, Zeplin, Photoshop
- Node.js
- Responsive Design, Web Animations

Summary & Objective

I'm having **5+ years of experience** working in a corporate environment as a **Front-end and UI developer**. Strong technical skills in complex web app development including web-based applications. Experience in **system analysis**, **design**, **workflow architecture**, **development**, **testing**, **and maintenance** of web-based applications.

Work History

Senior Software Engineer

- July 2021 - Current

Encora, Bangalore

• Using Angular as a framework to create a Single Page Application (SPA) that can bind data to specific views and synchronize data with the server using Rest API, HTML, SASS, TypeScript, and Angular.

UI Developer

- April 2020 - July 2021

Testsigma, Bangalore

 Built Automated Testing Web Applications using Angular 2+, HTML, JavaScript, TypeScript, MVC, and SCSS by following the agile-sprint methodology.

Front End Developer

- November 2017 - March 2020

GoProtoz, Bangalore

 Created the Website and Web Apps using Angular, HTML, SCSS, and JavaScript, and also implemented the responsiveness for both mobile and desktop platforms.

Web Designer

- April 2017 - November 2017

Spiderwebindia, Bangalore

 Developed the Front End User Interface using HTML, JavaScript, jQuery, and CSS. Responsible for code optimizing and testing across browsers with proper SEO concepts.

Education Details

B.E - Electronics & Communication Eng. - (2013 - 2017) - 74% K.S.Rangasamy College of Technology - Tiruchengode

Higher Secondary School (HSC) - (2012 - 2013) - 87% Sengunthar Higher Secondary School - Salem

Secondary School Leaving Certificate (SSLC) - (2010 - 2011) - 93% Sengunthar Higher Secondary School - Salem

Projects

https://app.testsigma.com/

https://sankar-covid-tracker.netlify.app/

https://sankar-shopping-demo.netlify.app/

https://sankar-weather-info.netlify.app/

https://sankar-web-streaming.netlify.app/

https://sankar-data-display.netlify.app/home

http://acmefacade.com/

https://navzakti.com/